INSPIRED BY TRUE EVENTS
Goddamn it.
Yes!
Yes. I'm coming.
NEW RECORDING
It's estimated that 50 billion euros worth
of cocaine is sold in Europe every year.
Most of it arrives here.
in the port of Rotterdam.
My mother always said. "People will do
crazy things for a little money."
I can tell you.
from what I see here every day:
People do even crazier things
for a whole lot of money.
Criminals used to take care of business
in secret. far away from normal people.
In recent months drug-related violence
has spiraled in Rotterdam.
They murder each other on busy streets.
throw firework bombs
in quiet neighborhoods.
There's a war going on. and we still
don't know who's fighting who.
And that's why you're here.
and that's why we're here.
This new wiretapping unit will grant us
a lot more freedom to operate than before.
Wiretaps. Monitoring.
And that's why we're looking for the best.
You will be helping our detectives.
We'll play you a recording.
The task is simple:
Give us as many clues as possible
to solve the case.
-What did you hear?
-I heard yelling. I think.
Did you hear anything that could tell us
something about the location?
-A harbor? Or somewhere near a harbor.
-Any idea what nationality they are?
-Other helpful details?
-Something happens at the end.
but it's not clear to me exactly
what this is.
It's pretty tricky.
I have two maybes.
and that's me being generous.
"Generous." That's you. alright.
Hello.
-Hi. And you are?
-Roman Mertens.
-This is the job interview. right?
-Yeah. sure. Come on in.
Find the chair. Sam.
Mr. Mertens…
I'm sure you have a lot to offer.
but I don't think this is the job for you.
It won't work. practically speaking.
I'm sure you'll find a job
that will suit you perfectly.
Let's go. Sam.
Restaurant Rotonde. It's closed today.
They close every Tuesday.
How do you know what I'm looking up?
Each key makes a slightly different sound.
You can hear what I'm typing?
Best of luck with your search.
No. wait a minute.
I hear a boat.
Fairly far away.
And machinery. We're in the harbor.
But everything sounds very far away.
We're high up.
Probably on a crane.
In one of those cabins.
I hear a man.
He knocks on a window.
He's about 35.
His voice is a bit distorted.
His mouth is covered.
There's a Dutchman.
He's scared.
He's being threatened.
There's a second man as well.
He's being pushed.
The Dutch guy has been thrown off.
He fell for a long time.
Two hundred feet maybe.
That's not Turkish.
They're Uzbeks.
-That's quite a lot already. I think…
-A BMW i8.
What?
The car that drives away at the end
is a BMW i8. I'm absolutely positive.
Aren't there any cameras there?
Three point four ounces.
Hey. you kept the curtains shut again.
Hey. handsome.
-My hands are dirty. sorry.
-I don't care. Hello.
Hello.
-Flemish vol-au-vent.
-I think it's my best work yet.
Wow. that smells great.
-Yeah. it does.
-Fuck! Sorry. I'm so stupid.
-Maybe you should take Sam.
-Sorry.
Sam. no. Didn't you learn
you can't just eat everything?
-Go to your bed.
-He listens to you as well as I do.
That's hilarious.
-Thank you.
-Very funny.
-You're sweet. Thank you.
-Yeah?
-Okay. great.
-And? How was your day?
Well…
-Something happened today.
-Oh dear.
-I left the call center.
-What?
Did you resign?
I did.
Caro. it's okay. I already have a new job.
With the police. The wiretapping unit.
I start on Monday.
You're kidding me.
Rom…
I simply asked. "How was your day?"
Most people would answer.
"Fine." or. "Good."
And you give me this. Geez…
You're completely insane.
-It's going to be fine.
-Yeah.
VETERINARY CLINIC VERHULST
-Alright.
-Yes? Okay. Here we go.
Okay.
Walk to the end of this street
until you reach the traffic lights.
Take the crosswalk there.
Be careful of the tram tracks.
Then go right into the park.
and after about 150 yards
make a right at the railing.
And that's where the water taxi stop is.
-Walk to the end of this street…
-I can't listen to this.
-That's what I hear all the time.
-Yes. I know.
I guess I'm used to it.
Hey. but maybe we could try it
with a more sultry voice?
To relieve my frustration in traffic.
I think I need that.
Sure. okay.
Why do you want to join the police
so badly?
The call center was…
fine. right?
I can finally show what I can do.
Something no one else can.
Do you understand?
I do.
-Hey. feel this.
-What?
He kicked.
Then you take the water taxi.
But it's soaking wet. just like me.
And then you come really hard…
to the Boompjeskade.
POLICE
Erwin! Erwin. come on. turn it off!
What will the neighbors think?
Let's see… Are there any bandits here
I need to arrest?
No!
I'm going to catch them.
Roman and Bo Mertens.
you are under arrest!
Roman. let Dad read.
Bo Mertens. you are under arrest!
Come on. we almost got them! Bang. bang!
Pull over here! To the right. come on!
Now put on the sirens! Bang. bang!
Come on. keep going! We almost lost them!
Drive. straight on!
To the left! Faster! Come on. keep going!
We almost lost them!
Roman!
Roman?
His optic nerve has been damaged.
INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND
PURPERHEIDE
How can we still not know anything?
Canvassing turned up nothing.
and Toon Sneyder's colleagues
have no idea what he was involved in.
Maybe it was his ex.
Sure. they hired two Uzbeks
to throw him off a crane.
-Stranger things have happened.
-That makes no sense.
-Maybe he supported Ajax.
-That must be it.
Roman. buddy! Over here.
-Is he really going to work here?
-We all have our disabilities. don't we?
Hey. These are your new coworkers.
That's Tess. Suus you've met.
And Safi's over there.
but he hardly ever says anything. so…
-Nice to meet you. I'm Roman.
-So you're really blind.
What a cute dog you have.
Oh. you're such a sweetheart.
What's his name?
-This is Sam.
-Hi. Sam. Hello.
-You're not supposed to pet him.
-Oh. right. Yes. I see now.
Nice one. Tess.
I'll show you your new workstation.
-Okay. cool.
-How do we do this?
-I'll put my hand on your…
-There.
What are you looking at? Go back to work.
-Hey. listen. we found that BMW of yours.
-Great.
It's from a car rental company.
and I know the owner.
Kirill Ergashev. He says
he has no idea who rented the car.
Bullshit of course. We put a tap on his
phone and you're going to listen to it.
We need to know his connection
to that crane guy.
-Okay. Fine. Eight steps.
-Huh?
-It's eight steps to the door.
-Depends on how long your legs are.
People. this is Roman.
He sees nothing. but he hears everything.
Hello.
This is your workstation.
Tony. have you found anything yet?
No. and for the thousandth time.
it's Anthony.
Tony's a grump. He's been here forever.
but he knows the system.
-so you can ask him anything.
-Okay.
That is…
-Helen. She's behind you.
-Hey.
It's her first day too.
What are we going to do with the dog?
If we can find a place for him.
he's happy. Right. Sam?
How do you work with computers?
I use a braille reader.
and all my devices have voice control.
We don't have that here
in the Middle Ages.
Tony. you help Roman for now.
-With what?
-With his files. so he can listen to them.
Okay.
Have fun.
Let me know if you need anything.
-Hi.
-Hey.
-I'll open up a file for you. so you can…
-Yes. go ahead.
We started tapping Kirill this morning.
This is from three hours ago.
Let me know when you're done
and I'll put on a new one.
Okay. cool. Thanks.
I've called him 100 times already.
I can't change that contract.
No. I really can't.
No. No. not right now. I'm at the garage.
All you do is work.
Isn't it time for a party?
Hey. turn that off!
Can't you see I'm on the phone?
What's the deal with those chips?
Shit. listen. there's a strike.
I don't have them yet.
-I expected them yesterday.
-I'll bring them by tomorrow.
-Then you're too late.
-The installation takes one minute.
-Excuses. Come on. man. focus.
-I'll take care of it.
Kirill?
Can I talk to you?
-About the accounts.
-No. I really need to get going.
The garage is giving me a headache.
Later. I promise.
-Sort it out. bro. and make it quick.
-No worries. it'll be alright.
Tony?
It's Anthony.
Yes. sorry.
Could you play a new clip for me?
-The previous one was nothing.
-I'll mark it as "not relevant".
All Ranges are gone.
But I still have a Lambo available.
That's a cool ride. man.
Tony?
There was an intermission
at the movie theater.
I said. "If I want to watch a movie
with breaks. I'll turn on the TV."
No. sweetie.
Okay. I'll stop by the supermarket.
I don't have a bag with me though.
-Okay. thanks.
-Here it comes.
Hello?
No. this is Kirill's phone.
Yes. this is his assistant speaking.
I'll make sure he calls you back. He's
in another important meeting right now.
No. I understand. I'll make sure
you call him back as soon as possible.
Or he'll call you back. that is.
You have a very nice day too. Okay. bye.
Rom?
Hey.
I don't have to worry. do I?
Worry? Why?
You know. you working for the police…
Is that safe?
Safe? Caro. I'm sitting behind a desk.
transcribing wiretaps.
Okay.
What's with that weird look?
Just something I heard
on the wiretap today.
What? Tell me.
That's a state secret.
If I tell you. I'll have to kill you.
Well…
-That would be a shame. Let's not do that.
-Agreed.
Come on. just a little bit further.
Okay. come on. go.
In Rotterdam a burning car was pushed
into the garage of a car rental company.
It's the fifth attack this week. and
probably connected to the recent drug war.
Why was Kirill's garage a target?
We suspect it's payback
for Toon Sneyder's death.
We'll have to step up the investigation
if we don't want to run the risk
of getting bogged down in…
Mrs. Limon.
Mr. De Geeter. Attacks are being
carried out in my city in broad daylight.
People are being pushed off cranes.
cars are being rammed into garages…
I'm here to find out what's going on.
Okay. but. Madam Mayor. I don't think
this is the time or the place to…
I give you the resources you ask for.
I give you the officers you ask for.
-Yes. thank you.
-What will you give me?
Like I said. I think
there's another time and place to…
We are global news. And I have no answers.
I can assure you
we're doing everything we can
to put a stop to this problem
as fast and efficiently as possible.
-Yes?
-Yes.
That's not the impression
I'm getting at all.
Mrs. Limon. if you want coffee. you'll
have to wait. I'm making a mess over here.
How do you know it's me?
I recognized the sound of your heels.
-Do you work here?
-I'm new. I'm in the wiretapping unit.
We don't have the right tools.
so I was wondering whether you…
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'll be right there. Yes.
We'll talk later.
Yes. okay.
-Theo. Old geezer.
-Nico.
Listen. kid. we compared your accounts
to the mileage on your cars.
and if they're correct. your rental cars
have driven two miles each.
-Does that sentence contain a question?
-It's all baloney.
You're not renting out cars.
you're laundering money.
And the question is: Who for?
You're in deep shit. man.
Just tell me what's going on.
Who would drive a burning car in here?
I know your dad. you know that.
We grew up together.
Does he know what you're doing
or should I give him a call?
Say hello to your old man.
Tell him he still owes me a twenty.
Aren't you done yet?
Police.
What are we going to do if he took a dump?
Then someone else will have
to clean it up. I can't.
-Why? Did he?
-No.
-Should I get you a little bag?
-If he had. I wouldn't tell you.
I've been to Kirill's.
He's still keeping his mouth shut.
Right.
That receptionist. Shania.
I would put a tap on her too.
-Why?
-She's sleeping with Kirill.
Isn't Kirill married?
He is.
-But I've heard some stuff.
-What kind of stuff?
You know. what Kirill was doing to her
during a phone call.
"Doing to her." What do you mean?
Well. he was…
With his mouth… on her.
Down there.
Doing that.
Eating pussy!
He was going down on her. Right?
And you recognized that sound.
Roman. you old perv.
Do you think that if I close my eyes.
I can hear stuff like that too?
Of course. Anyone can.
You just have to know what to listen for.
I had to learn as well.
You shouldn't try to look.
you should try to see.
Close your eyes.
Close your eyes and tell me something.
Why are you wearing sunglasses?
They're of no use to you.
Well. when the light is bright. my eyes
sometimes hurt. Say something else.
Let's go. Sparta!
Do you hear that? The closer my hand…
…the more muted.
You will learn.
I don't think I have a talent
for being blind.
That's more your thing.
We're putting a tap on Shania.
Let's see what else you can hear.
-And clean up that shit.
-What… But I can't see it.
You can smell it. can't you?
They think they can mess with me.
No. not like that. Fuck no.
And the police are just watching.
they don't do a thing.
-Give me your phone.
-No.
Give me your phone!
Call Nico.
I don't get why they bought him.
Some shady Belgian agent brought him in.
They already have three players like him.
Roman. this is Umut.
our go-to Uzbek interpreter.
-Let's hear what you've got.
-Yeah. sure.
He's calling a relative.
His uncle. I think.
They urgently need
to bring the family together.
They're going to pick a time
and let everyone know. That's it.
Are you sure? Their breathing
and heartbeat suggest they're angry.
Uzbek is a rather
aggressive-sounding language.
Will you listen again?
Do you think
I'll hear something different?
Too bad. I was hoping
we had something more.
-Nico. will you walk Umut out?
-You bet.
Semia said you haven't confirmed
the dinner yet.
That's Aniek's job.
As if I know our schedule.
We had an interpreter listen to it
and it was nothing.
So go home. Go to your girl.
Tomorrow's another day.
-I can clearly hear they're angry.
-Do you speak Uzbek?
Umut's been translating for us
for 16 years.
He's wrong. I'm telling you.
De Geeter and Suus didn't want you here.
I stuck my fucking neck out for you.
Don't make me regret it.
-Do I have to thank you or something?
-Have a nice evening!
It sucks. We're forced to buy a fence.
But all those fences are ugly.
You can't buy any pretty fences.
Yes. Bo. that's awful.
I really feel for you.
Yeah. alright.
-Hey. can I hold you for a minute?
-You want to go to Aunt Caro? Yes?
Yes! Then we can hit the buffet. Come.
Hello. sweetie. Isn't this nice.
Say hello to Uncle Roman.
Hello.
What's that?
No. No. no. no. Yes. I agree with you.
Yes. I also think
he's kind of quiet today.
Should we ask him how he's doing? Okay.
Uncle Roman. how are you doing?
I'm fine.
I know you like no other.
I don't know.
things are a bit tough at work.
It's not quite what I expected.
Don't be so impatient.
You only just started.
I'm sorry. but everyone struggles
in the beginning.
It was the same with the clinic.
When I started. no one came in.
I had to take on every…
Roman spilled the mayonnaise again.
Stop it!
But yeah… Are you even listening to me?
I'll be right back.
Where are you going?
Three. one. six. three. eight. two.
84.828.
Hello?
Hey. it's Roman.
-Roman?
-From the institute for the blind.
Roman Mertens?
-It's been a while. hasn't it?
-Yes. Wow. How did you get my number?
Sanne gave it to me.
I wanted to ask you something.
I need your help.
I don't understand.
We haven't spoken in 20 years.
I know. But I'm working for the police now
and it's really important.
Can you help me out?
-Who is that?
-An old friend. She speaks Uzbek.
Shouldn't you have cleared this first?
It's a breach of protocol. You can't just…
-Just play it.
-Okay. Mey. you can translate right along.
Okay.
It's Kirill.
Which line are you calling from?
A safe one. Not mine.
Did you hear what happened? Assholes.
They think they can mess with me.
In my garage.
Take it easy. okay?
Call the guys. Restaurant Het Hert.
On the river.
Friday. four p.m.
I have to go to the bathroom.
-Now?
-Yes.
We're almost there.
There's one on the boat.
I really have to go now.
I'll take her to that restaurant. Come on.
Let's go find a bathroom.
Your sister has a small bladder.
-Let's play "I spy".
-Alright.
I spy with my little eye… something green.
Is it the grass over there?
No. but you're close.
Okay. Is it… Is it the umbrella?
Yes. Now it's your turn.
The boss wants the war to end.
What's the plan? Make it rain bullets.
-You're kidding me.
-Fuck.
Everyone. to the Willemskade. now!
What happened?
I spy with my little eye…
something orange.
-Is it that car?
-How did you guess that so fast?
Okay. your turn again.
Okay. I spy with my little eye
something… black.
Mom. come on.
Stay down.
-Amaya?
-Bryan!
Call an ambulance!
You were right.
Umut screwed us over.
And a little girl got hurt.
Is it serious?
We're going to get them. goddamn it.
You and me.
Sorry. you can't pet my dog.
It confuses him a little.
Is it working out at the police. Roman?
Do I know you? Have we met before?
No. I didn't mean to scare you. I'm sorry.
But a few people I know
are very curious about the investigations
the police are conducting.
And then I thought.
Roman works for the police.
So he can probably tell us some things.
A little talking won't hurt anyone.
Are you trying to bribe me or something?
"Bribe" is a bit of an ugly word.
I have a business proposal for you.
I want you to leave me alone.
-Or else…
-Or else what?
You're going to call the cops?
You're going to tell your new colleagues?
You can. but I do wonder what your
girlfriend Caro would think about that.
I saw that she's pregnant. Nice.
Boy or girl?
I hope everything goes well.
I can tell you need to think about it.
No problem. We'll meet again. alright?
See you soon. pal.
Bye.
NEXT TIME
How long have you been mistranslating?
And who for?
That guy is insane.
You saw what they do
to people who don't cooperate.
I once saw somebody pop
someone's eyeball out with a screwdriver.
That won't happen to you.
there's no point. but still.
Hey. Roman. Who you gonna call?
-What's wrong?
-We have to call Nico.